《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
APOLLO: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
就是它了 是它 爱奥尼亚星云
This is it. That's it. The lonian Nebula.
你说我们会有何发现?  信标?  神庙?
So what do you think we'll find? A beacon? Temple?
通往地球的路标?
Signpost to Earth?
还有多少次跳跃才能找到那座星云?
How many more jumps before we find the nebula?
我估计要十二次
I'm estimating an even dozen.
快了 仍旧没有赛昂人的影子
We're getting close. Still no sign of the Cylons.
我没听到你们说的什么…
SKULLS: I didn't hear you nuggets say that...
往回调  就差一点
SAM: There. Go back. You almost had it.
什么差一点?
SEELIX: Had what?
那首曲子  你没听到?
That song. You don't hear that song?
在他娘的船里!
It's in the frakking ship!
这是我的儿子
This is my son.
节哀顺变 但这不是我的责任
I am very sorry for your loss, but I am not responsible.
我知道  他病了 我求你保佑他
I know. He's sick, and I want you to bless him.
保佑他?
Bless him?
您是说被告盖尤斯・波塔尔...
You are saying that the defendant, Gaius Baltar, ordered your execution
下令处决您和其他200名民众?
and the execution of 200 other people?
正是如此
That is exactly what I am saying.
这是一份死刑执行令 你看过这份名单上的名字吗?
This is a death warrant. Have you seen the names on this list?
你知道他们会怎么做吗?
Do you have any idea what they're about to do out there?
盖尤斯・波塔尔选择与赛昂人为伍
Gaius Baltar chose to side with the Cylons
并主动迫害他的子民
and to actively seek the deaths of his fellow citizens.
总统阁下 您此时是否服用了卡马拉?
Madam President, are you taking chamalla at this time?
不用回答他 这场审判到此为止
Don't answer. I'm putting a stop to this right now.
法官大人 如果她服用了此药
Your Honors, if she is on drugs,
她作为证人的可信度理应受到质疑
it goes to her credibility as a witness.
我再次服用卡马拉是因为我的癌症复发了
I am taking chamalla again because my cancer has returned.
你是一个骗子和孬种
ADAMA: I'm calling you a liar and a coward.
为了什么?
And for what?
就为了那个背信弃义的垃圾 盖尤斯・波塔尔么?
That traitorous piece of garbage Gaius Baltar.
他就不配得到审判
He doesn't even deserve a trial.
我不会为一个质疑我忠诚的人效力
I will not serve under a man who questions my integrity.
我也不会让一名欠缺此种品质的人
And I won't have an officer under my command
做我部下
who doesn't have any.
妈的
Frak me.
喂?
Yes.
骂我一顿 我不想下床
Yell at me. I don't want to get out of bed.
你打错电话了 我正要去睡觉
Well, you called the wrong number. I was just thinking about going back to bed.
你感觉还好吧?
You feeling okay?
身患绝症的人还好意思问我
Says the cancer patient.
恩  还好  刚划了自己一刀
Yeah, I'm fine. I just cut myself.
你怎么样?
How are you doing?
我不想去面对他们
I don't want to face them.
不想去面对他们任何人 只想整天躺在床上睡觉
I don't want to face any of them. I just want to stay in bed all day and sleep.
我已经把血止住了
I think I've stopped the bleeding.
如果还想找人教训你 我可以代劳
If you still need to be yelled at, I think I can give you some volume.
好 好 尽全力来吧
Okay. All right. Give it your best shot.
从床上下来!
Get out of that bed!
你没尽全力
That's not your best shot.
罗丝琳 把你的大屁股从床上挪下来
Get your fat, lazy ass out of that rack, Roslin!
是  长官    遵命  长官
Yes, sir. Okay, sir. Anything you say, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
别让他们看到你焦虑不安的样子 劳拉
Don't let them see you sweat, Laura.
过来
Come here.
不行
I can't.
来吧
Come here.
我得回殖民者一号
I've got to go back to Colonial One.
你哪都不能去
You don't have to go anywhere.
这是什么音乐?  天啊
What is that music? Gods.
你刚才说什么?
What did you just say?
惨了
Frak.
好  来了
Yeah. I'm coming.
为什么锁门?
Hey. Why is the door locked?
不好意思
Sorry.
我们应该采取失审这一招 译注:即再次重新审理
We should go for a mistrial.
什么?  他是什么意思?
What? What's he talking about?
你什么意思啊?  失审?  为什么?
What are you talking about? A mistrial? Whatever for?
因为我们处于劣势
Because we're losing.
我可没看出来
Not from where I'm standing.
我们其实做得很好啊
We're actually doing quite well.
我们就快要把控方压倒了
We're just about to break the prosecution.
我们已把他们的两名关键证人拉下了马
We've blown two of their key witnesses out of the water.
我们还要怎么做啊?
What more do we need to do, for Gods' sakes?
在场的每个人都对你恨之入骨 每个人 包括法官们
Everyone in that courtroom hates you. Everyone. Including the judges.
你还没听到我父亲叫你什么
You didn't hear what my father just called you.
他说你是一个背信弃义的垃圾
He called you "a traitorous piece of garbage. "
说你不配得到审判
A man who doesn't even deserve a trial.
他是那么说的么?  真那么说了?
He said that? He actually said that?
对  不错
Yes, he did.
我看不只他一个人这么想
And I don't think he's the only one up there.
我同意 我们的战术胜利让他们大动肝火
I agree. Our tactical victories are pissing them off.
那我们现在得势反倒变成失势了?
Right. So, now, because we're winning, we're losing, actually.
有违常理  对吧?  这也是我热爱这份工作的原因之一
Perverse, isn't it? One of the reasons why I love what I do.
"强行使用失审表面看来 也许对双方都有利
"Forcing a mistrial may seem of little benefit to either side,
但实际上 对辩方来讲不失为一份恩惠
"but in fact, it can be a boon to the defense.
控方已经摊牌 当复审时
"The prosecution's shown their hand. At retrial, the defense has
辩方拥有一切战术优势
"all the tactical advantages
且被判为无罪的机会 将上升25个百分点"
"and the statistical chances of an acquittal rise by 25%."
乔瑟夫・亚当玛著
"Joseph Adama. "
第237页上的"审判战术与策略"
"Trial Tactics and Strategies," page 273.
你的祖父是一位聪明人
Smart man, your grandfather.
我明白你为什么要走失审这步棋了
Yeah, well, I can see why you want a mistrial.
不好意思  你这是什么意思?
I'm sorry. What is that supposed to mean?
这是你推卸责任…
Well, that would be the quickest way, wouldn't it?
最快的办法
For you to absolve all of your responsibility.
放下这个烂摊子一走了之 返回到你自己的生活
Wash your hands of the whole affair. You get back to your life.
你返回到属于你的地方
You get back to wherever you get back to.
而我却要回到牢里 再经历一次这种事
And I get back to a cell, and I have to go through this all over again.
我身体上无法承受这一切了
I can't physically take that!
不要策略 不要失审
No more games. No mistrials.
只求一个判决结果
There will be a verdict.
昨日对盖尤斯・波塔尔博士的审判
Yesterday marked a surprising
当泰上校承认杀死了自己妻子时
turn of events in the trial of Dr. Gaius Baltar,
上演了令人惊讶的逆转
when Colonel Tigh admitted to killing his wife.
在你们这群菜鸟想驾机上天之前
Before any of you nuggets can even think about flying one of my Raptors,
你们必须熟悉了解飞行系统 电子元件  航空控制系统
you have to know Systems, Electronics, Avionics,
导航系统  引擎控制系统
Navigation, Engine Controls,
雷达配置 超光速引擎
Dradis Configuration, Basic FTL Functions,
自动驾驶装置 动力装置
Autopilot Gearing, and Propulsion Systems.
掌握这些知识最快的办法是要登上猛禽
The best way to learn that is on a Raptor,
就是说要实践操作
and that means getting your hands dirty.
来吧
Move. Come on.
过来 快 上来
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
嗨 山姆
Hey, Sam.
你哼的是什么曲子?
That song you're humming. What is that?
哦…
Oh. Uh...
连我自己都不知道
You know what? I don't even know.
这首曲子一直在我脑中回荡
It's just something I can't get out of my head.
挥之不去
Some way out of here.
我也一直听到这种声音
I've been hearing that.
无处不在 在收音机中 在酒吧里
Everywhere. On a boombox, you know? In the bar.
到这边来
Come here.
你也听到那首曲子了?
You hear that song?
是啊  把我吓坏了
Yeah. And it's freaking me out.
我走到哪里都能听到 可又听不清
I hear it everywhere. I mean... But I can't really hear it.
你懂我的意思么?
Do you know what I mean?
懂 就像是你刚抓住一段旋律
Yeah. It's like you can grab just a part of the melody,
而它又马上消失了 像是一段…
and then it goes away, like it's something from...
童年的记忆
BOTH: Childhood.
正是
Exactly.
安德斯!  你还用我他妈叫你吗?
Yo, Anders! Do you need a frakking invitation?
快来!
Move it!
来啦 用不着那么激动吧
All right. No reason to get excited.
恭喜你 你从你的第一次 "呔唠醺"疗法中挺了过来
Well, congratulations. You survived your first Doloxan treatment.
真是以毒攻毒啊
Talk about the cure being worse than the disease.
下次带本书或一些书面文件
Well, next time, bring a book or some paperwork.
这样有助于帮你分散注意力
It would help keep your mind off of it,
还能帮助降压
and it would also help keep your blood pressure down.
可得了吧
Yeah, right.
失陪了
Now, if you'll excuse me,
我还有其他病人
I do have some other patients.
好  去吧
All right. Go.
真要命
Oh, Gods.
赫拉!
Hera!
怎么回事?
COTTLE: What's going on?
你们俩怎么同时惊叫了起来?
You're both freaking out at the same time?
我们要单独呆一会 请把这东西拿下来
We need a moment. Take this off. Get this off me, please.
谁能告诉我到底怎么回事?
Will somebody please tell me what the hell is going on?
出去吧 谢谢 我们不会有事 把门关上
You can go outside. Thank you. We'll be fine. Shut the door.
是  阁下
GUARD: Yes, ma'am.
不好意思  给你带上了手铐
I'm sorry about the shackles.
刚才你是否和我们...
Were you with us a moment ago?
在一座歌剧院的大厅里?
In the lobby of the opera house?
看你脸上的表情  我想是了
I'll take that as a yes, by the look on your face.
我当时也在场 赫拉也在
I was there, too. And so was Hera.
那是不可能的
That shouldn't be possible.
不可能的事多着呢
Add it to the list.
你当时是想得到赫拉么?
Were you trying to reach Hera?
不知道
I don't know.
我只知道自己 要竭尽全力保护她
I just knew that I had to protect her with my life.
我告诉你  比尔  他们在这船上放音乐  我能听到
I'm telling you, Bill, they've put the music in the ship. I can hear it.
我相信你 我会调查一下
I believe you. I'll look into it.
你会调查?
You'll look into it?
我可是在说赛昂人在我们的船上搞破坏
I am here telling you there is Cylon sabotage aboard our ship!
用音乐搞破坏?
Sabotage? With music?
我自己也不是很明白
I know, I know.
不过有许多事情令人迷惑不解
I can't quite understand it myself, but there's too much confusion.
我保证会去调查的
I promise I'll look into it.
现在我要去法庭了
Now, I have to get to court.
好
Okay.
去法庭吧
You go to court.
一定有出去的办法
There must be some kind of way out of here.
你认识这份文件吗  中尉?
Do you recognize this document, Lieutenant?
是的  认识
Yes, I do.
这是一份由新卡布里卡上总统办公室签发的死刑名单
It's a death list issued on New Caprica by the office of the President.
是谁签署的这份文件?
Who signed this document?
盖尤斯・波塔尔总统
President Gaius Baltar.
它有可能是伪造的吗?
Could it be a forgery?
不可能
No.
你怎么知道不是伪造的?
And how do you know that it cannot be a forgery?
因为当时我在场亲眼看他签的字
Because I was there. I saw him sign it.
什么?
BALTAR: What?
你在胡说什么?  你不在场!  真是谎话连篇
What are you talking about? You weren't there! That's a lie!
完全是在捏造事实
That's a total fabrication!
肃静!
FRANKS: Order!
我看到他签了字
I saw him sign it.
描述一下当时的情况  好吗?
Describe the scene, would you?
赛昂人把这份文件 带到了总统办公室
The Cylons brought the document to the Presidential office.
他们已经选定了名字
They'd already selected the names.
他们当中一人 我相信是一名三号
One of them, I believe it was a Three,
她把那份名单递给总统  然后说道:
gave the list to the President and said,
"这些是即将被处决的人  请签字"
"Here are the people that are going to be executed. Please, sign this. "
他看着名单  看到名单上的名字
He looked at the list, he saw all the names,
然后签了字
and then he signed it.
他反对过吗?  他是否争执过?
Did he protest? I mean, did he argue?
是否做出了任何反抗举动?
Did he offer any resistance whatsoever?
签字
Sign it!
我不会签的
I won't do it.
去找别的方法减轻你的负罪感吧
You're going to have to salve your consciences some other way.
签字!  签上你的名字!  签上!
Sign it! Sign your name! Sign it!
没有 他从没那么做过
No. He never did.
菲里克斯
Oh, Felix.
菲里克斯  你这是干什么?
Oh, Felix. What are you doing?
拿到一边去
Get that out of my face...
盖尤斯 我们在诘问的时候再揭穿他
Gaius, it's okay, we'll get him on cross.
律师  让你的委托人克制一下好吗?
Counsel, will you control your client?
这不是什么新鲜事
Look, it's no secret!
安静  整个舰队都知道这个人
Quiet. The whole fleet knows this man tried
想除我而后快  你没得手!  蠢货!
to stab me through the neck! And you missed! Butterfingers!
抱歉  法官大人  闭嘴
Sorry, Your Honors. Shut up.
没有问题了
No further questions.
该你讯问证人了  律师
Your witness, Counselor.
我没有问题
No questions.
什么?!
What?
你怎么…
What, are you...
证人退庭
The witness is dismissed.
这可好
BALTAR: Oh, great.
你这是干什么?
BALTAR: What the hell are you doing?
你们俩现在是各执一词
Listen, it's your word against his right now.
如果他已决定做伪证  我们也无能为力
If he's decided to perjure himself, there's nothing we can do to change that now.
我们要调整一下策略
We'll have to adjust our strategy.
辩方做好辩护准备了吗?
Is the defense prepared to present their case?
法官大人...
Your Honors.
现在  如果庭上允许
At this time, if it please the court,
我想提出一个动议
I would like to offer a motion.
辩方想要提议失审
The defense would like to move for a mistrial.
不  我们不想要失审  我不要失审
No! We do not want a mistrial! I do not want a mistrial!
盖尤斯・波塔尔!
Gaius Baltar!
注意举止  波塔尔博士
Behave, Dr. Baltar.
以什么为依据  律师?
On what grounds, Counselor?
庭上一位法官
On the grounds that one of the panel
已对审判结果做出预断 (译注:即提前决定)
has already prejudged the outcome of this trial and determined the guilt
并裁定被告有罪
of the defendant.
这可是一项非常严重的指控 拉姆金先生
ADAMA: That's a very serious charge, Mr. Lampkin.
哪位法官?
Which judge?
那就是你  上将
That would be you, Admiral.
为了证明此事 我要采取非常措施
And to prove it, I need to take the unusual step
传李・亚当玛先生出庭作证
of calling Mr. Lee Adama to the stand.
你他妈在开玩笑吧
You've got to be frakking kidding me.
盖塔已把我们推下水
Gaeta sunk us.
我们惟有以此才能取胜
This is the only way we're going to win.
我不会做出对我父亲不利的证言
I will not testify against my father.
那由你来决定 无论如何 我都要让你出庭作证
That is your choice. Either way, I'm putting you on the stand.
法官大人 这样做根本不合适
Your Honors. This is completely improper.
法律顾问在任何情况下 都不能出庭作证
Counsel cannot testify at trial under any circumstances.
我随口可以举出至少七个这样的先例
I can cite at least seven precedents off the top of my head.
传唤你的证人  律师
Call your witness, Counselor.
谢谢
Thank you.
亚当玛先生
Mr. Adama.
亚当玛先生 你是否与你的父亲亚当玛上将在四天前见过面?
Mr. Adama, did you meet with your father, Admiral Adama, four days ago?
是的
Yes.
在那次见面的时候 亚当玛上将是否就被告应否
At that meeting, did Admiral Adama express an opinion
得到审判这一点发表过个人看法?
as to whether the defendant deserved a trial?
我只想知道事实真相  亚当玛先生  请讲
All I'm looking for is the truth, here, Mr. Adama. Let's have it.
我在等着 回答问题
I'm waiting. Answer the question.
你以军官的身份 曾在这法庭上发过誓
You swore an oath as an officer of the court.
如果你不回答问题 你就会使整套司法体制…
If you don't answer the question, you hold the entire system of justice...
什么他妈的体制?
What frakking system?
亚当玛先生!
Mr. Adama!
抱歉  法官大人
I'm sorry, Your Honor.
请原谅我的同事
Please excuse my associate.
好吧  好吧  我换个问题
All right, all right. I'll try something else.
你认为被告应得到公正的审判吗?
Do you believe that the defendant deserves a fair trial?
事实上  我认为是的      为什么?
As a matter of fact, I do. Why?
抛开每人都理应得到 公正的审判这一事实不说
Well, aside from the fact that everyone deserves a fair trial,
我恰恰相信他没有罪
I also happen to believe that he is not guilty of the charges
应当被无罪释放
and should be acquitted.
法官大人  我必须坚持反对
Your Honors, I must insist on an exception here!
他不能采用这种方式作证 这根本不合适
He cannot testify in this manner. It's completely improper.
我同意 他可以在结案陈词中
I agree. He can make his arguments
阐述此观点 不能在作证时说
in closing statements, not on the stand.
我同意控方所说的这一点
I'm inclined to agree with the prosecution.
谢谢
CASSIDY: Thank you.
如果你认为此做法影响了判决结果 你可以向总统上诉
You can appeal to the President if you feel that this influences the verdict.
但就我个人来讲...
But I, for one,
想听一下这位证人作证
would like to hear this witness testify.
我赞成
MALE JUDGE: I would second that.
继续
Continue.
谢谢  法官大人
Thank you, Your Honors.
亚当玛先生
Mr. Adama?
Mr. Adama!
在
Yes?
你为何认为被告盖尤斯・波塔尔是无罪的?
Why do you believe that the defendant, Gaius Baltar, deserves to be acquitted?
因为没有证据能证明他所受到的指控
Well, because the evidence does not support the charges.
不是吧
Come on.
被告有过错吗?
Did the defendant make mistakes?
当然有
Sure. He did.
严重的错误 但他真的犯了什么罪吗?
Serious mistakes. But did he actually commit any crimes?
他犯了叛国罪吗?  没有
Did he commit treason? No.
当时的情况非人力可抗拒
I mean, it was an impossible situation.
当赛昂人到来之时  他又能怎么办?
When the Cylons arrived, what could he possibly do?
谁又能做些什么?
What could anyone have done?
各位扪心自问  你们会怎么做?
I mean, ask yourself. What would you have done?
你们又能做些什么?
What would you have done?
如果他拒绝投降 赛昂人可能当即
If he had refused to surrender, the Cylons would have probably
就会用核弹炸平整个星球
nuked the planet right then and there.
他和赛昂人合作了?  当然
So, did he appear to cooperate with the Cylons? Sure.
其他数百名民众也一样
So did hundreds of others.
他和他们又有什么不同?
What's the difference between him and them?
总统发布了一条集体赦免令
The President issued a blanket pardon.
他们都被赦免了  未被审问
They were all forgiven. No questions asked.
泰上校
Colonel Tigh.
泰上校利用自杀式炸弹袭击者杀死了几十人 被赦免
Colonel Tigh used suicide bombers and killed dozens of people. Forgiven.
阿格森中尉和蒂罗尔轮机长
Lieutenant Agathon and Chief Tyrol.
他们在帕伽索斯上杀害了一名军官 被赦免
They murdered an officer on the Pegasus. Forgiven.
上将 上将针对总统发动了一场…
The Admiral... The Admiral instituted a military coup d'etat
军事政变
against the President.
被赦免
Forgiven.
而我呢?
And me?
呃
Well...
我该从何说起?
Where do I begin?
我击落了一艘民用船
I shot down a civilian passenger ship.
奥林匹克号 船上载有千余名民众 被赦免
The Olympic Carrier. Over a thousand people on board. Forgiven.
我把枪口对准上级
I raised my weapon to a superior officer.
发动兵变 被赦免
Committed an act of mutiny. Forgiven.
而就在波塔尔向赛昂人俯首称臣的那天
And then, on the very day when Baltar surrendered to those Cylons,
我作为帕伽索斯的指挥官临阵脱逃
I, as commander of the Pegasus, jumped away!
把手无寸铁的民众单独丢在那颗星球上达数月之久
I left everybody on that planet, alone, undefended, for months!
我甚至还劝说上将永远不要回来
I even tried to persuade the Admiral never to return.
为求自保 把你们全丢在这里
To abandon you all there for good.
如果按我说的去做 没人能离开那颗星球
If I'd had my way, nobody would have made it off that planet.
我才是懦夫 我才是叛徒
I'm the coward. I'm the traitor.
而我被赦免了
I'm forgiven.
我不得不说 我们对待错误很宽容
I'd say we're very forgiving of mistakes.
我们制定了自己的法律 自己的司法
We make our own laws now, our own justice,
而从偷窃到谋杀 我们在寻找使大家
and we've been pretty creative at finding ways to let people off the hook
免受法律制裁的方法上极富创造力
for everything from theft to murder.
我们只能这样 因为…
And we've had to be. Because...
因为我们不再是一个文明的社会
Because we're not a civilization anymore.
我们是一群乌合之众 我们在逃亡
We are a gang. And we're on the run.
我们必须拼命活下来 必须破例
And we have to fight to survive! We have to break rules!
必须枉法 必须因人而异
We have to bend laws! We have to improvise!
可这次却不行  不行
But not this time. No.
这次不行
Not this time.
对盖尤斯・波塔尔就不行
Not for Gaius Baltar.
不 你!
No. You!
你必须死
You have to die.
你必须死  因为我们非常不喜欢你
You have to die because, well, because we don't like you very much.
因为你自大 因为你软弱
Because you're arrogant. Because you're weak.
因为你是一个孬种
Because you're a coward.
我们是暴民  我们要把你扔出过渡舱
And we, the mob, we want to throw you out the airlock
因为你没有反抗赛昂人 没有光荣牺牲
because you didn't stand up to the Cylons and get yourself killed in the process
这就是现在的司法
That's justice now!
你就应该在新卡布里卡上丧命
You should have been killed back on New Caprica,
可因为你苟且偷生  我们就要处决你
but since you had the temerity to live, we're going to execute you now!
这就是司法!
That's justice!
肃静  肃静
Order. Order!
这个案件...
This case...
是建立在私人情感之上 建立在愤怒…
This case is built on emotion. On anger.
怨恨… 报复之上
Bitterness. Vengeance.
然而最根本的 还是建立在耻辱之上
But most of all, it is built on shame.
是在那颗星球上
It's about the shame
我们对自己人那些所作所为的耻辱
of what we did to ourselves back on that planet.
是我们之中...
And it's about the guilt
那些充当逃兵的人的内疚
of those of us who ran away.
那些充当逃兵的人
Who ran away.
而我们却要把全部罪责与耻辱  都推卸到那一个人身上
And we are trying to dump all that guilt and all that shame onto one man,
然后把他冲出过渡舱
and then flush him out the airlock
希望这一切都随之而去
and hope that, that just gets rid of it all!
这样我们就能够心安理得
So that we can live with ourselves.
这样做是徒劳的
But that won't work.
是徒劳的 那不是公正
That won't work. That's not justice.
对我来说不是
Not to me.
没有问题了
No further questions.
法官大人 我希望再次重申一下
Your Honors, I wish to reiterate my strong exception
我强烈反对辩方法律顾问作证
to defense counsel's testimony.
我们已经注意到了
FRANKS: Exception noted.
谢谢
Thank you.
你想诘问证人吗?
Did you want to cross-examine the witness?
我没有问题要问辩方法律顾问
I have no questions for defense counsel.
证人请退庭
FRANKS: Witness is excused.
你还要传唤其他证人吗?
Do you want to call any other witnesses?
法官大人
Your Honors,
我不想再拖延下去了
I don't wish to belabor this any longer.
辩方停止辩护
The defense rests.
很好
FRANKS: Very well.
法庭休庭  商议判决
This court will adjourn to consider a verdict.
这真是法学史上一个辉煌的时刻
What a glorious moment in jurisprudence.
你做得很好
You did a great job.
全体起立
GUARD: All rise!
在宣布判决结果之前  我想先说明一件事
Before I read the verdict, I'd like to make one thing clear.
如同人类一样 司法制度并非尽善尽美
Like everything human, justice is imperfect.
它有瑕疵
It's flawed.
然而正是这些不足之处
But it's those very imperfections
使得我们有别于那些机器
that separates us from the machines.
甚至可能让我们成为一个值得挽救的物种
And maybe even makes us a species worth saving.
被告请起立
The defendant will rise.
盖尤斯・波塔尔
Gaius Baltar,
在认真权衡证据之后
after carefully weighing the evidence,
本庭以3票对2票的投票结果...
this tribunal, on a vote of three to two,
宣判你无罪
finds you not guilty.
你赢了 当心
You earned it. Watch out.
走吧
Let's go.
我就知道我是无罪的
I always knew that I was going to be acquitted.
但即便判我无罪也无法掩盖...
The fact that I've been found innocent shouldn't disguise in any way
这场审判是 一次彻头彻尾的暗箱操作
that this trial has been a total pantomime.
上将  得把他弄出去!
Admiral! We've got to get him out of here!
下来 让他下来
Down! Get him down!
让他回来  把他弄出去!
Get him back! Get him out of here!
我从一开始就知道总有办法证明...
I knew right from the very start that if there was a way to demonstrate
这一套纯属…  那个词叫什么来着?
the sheer... What's the word I'm looking for?
弄虚作假 我说的就是弄虚作假
"Hypocrisy. " "Hypocrisy" is the word I'm looking for.
控方的证据弄虚作假
Hypocrisy of the prosecution's case,
法官们别无选择  只能判我无罪
then, really, the judges had no other option but to find me not guilty.
你信心十足的样子在整个过程中
Well, your boundless confidence provided us with great solace
给予我们莫大的安慰
throughout the proceedings.
谢谢你们俩
Look, I want to thank you both.
真的
Truly.
我从心底十分感激你们为我所做的一切
From the bottom of my heart. I am very, very grateful
个人来讲...
for all you've done.
我能再看会上将那坐立不安的样子
On a personal note, if I could have seen the Admiral squirm just a little bit more
我也无所谓    你给听好
it wouldn't have hurt. Now, you listen!
别得了便宜还卖乖  博士
Don't push it, Doctor.
好
Fine.
罗默 我们可能应该谈一下
Romo, perhaps we could have a chat.
能否在舰队里举行一个签售活动
I've thought about maybe doing a book tour around the fleet.
还有版权问题
And there's the publishing rights. There are issues about my security,
还有我住行的安全问题
where I'm going to live, what I'm going to do.
既然咱们通过这场审判 建立了这么深厚的友谊
Since we forged this great relationship during the trial,
我想还有谁比你们更…
I thought, you know, who better to... Think about...
事实上  舰队的法律制度已经健全
Actually, now that the fleet's legal system is in place,
其他地方还需要我这不顾他人安危的天份
my not-so-inconsiderable talents are required elsewhere.
所以恐怕我们的缘分到此了
So, I'm afraid this is the end of our journey.
等一下  等…   那我呢?
What? Wait a minute. What... What about me?
请等一下  等等
Wait a minute. Wait. Please.
你们想一下
Think about this for a second.
我要住在哪里?  我该怎么办?
Where am I going to live? What am I going to do?
我要怎么活下去啊?
How am I going to survive?
我不想用"一只猫"的那个比喻  博士
Much as I hate to use a cat metaphor, Doctor,
我想你会找到栖身之所的
I think you'll land on your feet.
出去的时候把门关上
Close the door on your way out.
罗默  还有件事
Romo, one thing...
当你让我出庭作证的时候
When you put me on the stand,
你已经知道结果了么?
did you know what was going to happen?
我知道你是一个诚实的人 亚当玛先生
I knew you were an honest man, Mr. Adama,
一点也不像你的祖父
much unlike your grandfather.
盖尤斯・波塔尔是无辜的
Gaius Baltar is innocent.
单听这么一说  我都浑身难受
Just the sound of that makes my skin crawl.
无罪并不等于无辜
Not guilty is not the same as innocent.
一定是让你很伤脑筋吧
Must have been particularly difficult for you.
你就...
What, you just...
不能让其他两个人做出让步么?
You couldn't get the other two guys to budge?
你投了无罪  对吧?
You voted for his acquittal, didn't you?
我不想这么说
I hate to say it.
辩方的理由充分
Defense made their case.
控方就不行了
Prosecution didn't.
且不说这次审判的结果 你我都心知肚明
Gaius Baltar is a traitor. We both know that.
盖尤斯・波塔尔是个叛徒
Regardless of the outcome of his trial.
这并不是说 就让大家忘记…
No one's asking anyone to forget.
或饶恕这一切
Or to forgive.
但我们必须向前看
But we have to look to the future.
盖塔先生    是  长官
Mr. Gaeta. Sir?
开始跳跃准备
Commence jump prep.
我们去爱奥尼亚星云
We're going to the lonian Nebula.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
请原谅
Excuse me.
跳跃坐标已传达完毕  长官
GAETA: Jump coordinates have been distributed, sir.
各船显示D式跳跃阵型
All fleet ships show green for jump formation delta.
开始跳跃
Initiate jump.
是  长官
Aye, sir.
跳跃倒计时 三 二 一
Jumping in three, two, one...
跳跃
Jump.
完成跳跃
GAETA: Jump complete.
各船报告完毕  长官
All fleet ships reporting in, sir.
非常好  盖塔先生
Very well, Mr. Gaeta.
开始雷达扫描
Commence dradis scan.
查看周围情况
Let's see what's out there.
呃
Uh...
哦
Oh...
报告情况     我们的传感器显示有巨大的能量波动
ADAMA: Sitrep! GAETA: Sensors show major power fluctuations.
正检查整个舰队
Checking on fleet.
守卫 两英尺远
MAN: Guards, two feet over!
菜鸟跟我来!  菜鸟跟我来!
RACETRACK: Nuggets on me! Nuggets on me!
有手电筒就 打开
CALLY: If you have a flashlight, turn it on!
检查辅助电源
GAETA: Check auxiliary power.
我们没有辅助电源 只是在靠电池维持
DUALLA: We have negative auxiliary power. We're on batteries only.
做好引擎再启动准备
ADAMA: Get ready for an engine restart.
盖尤斯 别怕  跟我来
Gaius, it's okay. Come with me.
你们要带我去哪里?
Where are you taking me to?
寻找你的新生 来吧
To your new life. Come on.
来吧!  把电力恢复!
TYROL: Come on, let's get the power back up.
大家动起来  你们知道该怎么做
Come on, people, move it around, you know what to do.
大家靠在一起
RACETRACK: Come on. Get yourself together!
一定有出去的办法
There must be some kind of way out of here.
小心脚下
RACETRACK: Be careful where you walk.
到处都是设备 都是连电的
There's lots of equipment around. It's all live.
小丑对小偷如是说
Said the joker to the thief.
这里混乱不堪
There's too much confusion here.
让我一刻不得闲
I can't get no relief.
这不是真的
This isn't happening.
求你告诉我这不是真的
Please, tell me this isn't happening.
原来如此
So, that's it.
在历尽艰险之后
After all this time.
开关就这样一变
A switch goes off just like that.
哇
Whoa!
不是吧
No way.
我不信 我才不信 这是…
I don't believe this. I'm not buying this. This is...
这是骗人的把戏  拜托  我们可不是…
It's a trick. Come on, we're not...
那是什么…
What is that...
那首曲子是什么来着?
What is that song?
妈了个巴子的!  够了!
All right! That's enough, Gods damn it!
把门都他妈的锁上!
Deadbolt that frakking door!
入伍40年
Forty years in the service.
40年
Forty years.
参加过两次大战
Two wars.
参与作战
Combat.
在新卡布里卡上被关在那座地牢里
Locked in that dungeon on New Caprica.
艾伦
Ellen.
我的天
My Gods...
那艾伦又算作是什么?
What about Ellen?
不  不
No, no, no.
不可能
Not after all this.
不可能在反抗...
Not after the Resistance
和占领之后还会这样
and the occupation.
看着我的朋友一个个死去  就是他妈为了这个结果?
Not after watching my friends die, one after another, for frakking this?
山姆… 离我远点
Sam... You stay the hell away from me.
你们都他妈离我远点
You all just stay the frak away from me.
山姆
Sam...
是真的
It's true.
我们是赛昂人
We're Cylons.
从一开始就是
And we have been from the start.
上将  这是怎么回事?
ROSLIN: Admiral, what's going on?
好象是电涌吧
Some kind of power surge.
立即给我损坏报告
Give me a damage report, immediately.
断电是整个舰队范围的
The power outage is fleet-wide, Admiral.
所有船只几乎是同时恢复电力
It was also simultaneously restored to all ships.
上将 上将!
Admiral. Admiral!
雷达上出现目标
Dradis contact!
拦截航道上出现大规模赛昂舰队
Massive Cylon fleet on intercept course!
盖塔先生  立即下令各就各位
Mr. Gaeta, sound action stations immediately.
副长  全体舰队紧急跳跃
XO, I want emergency jump for the entire fleet.
长官 全体舰队在断电期间都消耗了动力
Sir, all fleet ships were powered down during the outage.
至少要用20分钟才能启动超光速引擎
It will take at least 20 minutes to spool up the FTL drives.
我们没有20分钟
We just don't have 20 minutes.
各就各位  各就各位
Action stations, action stations,
全体舰队一级戒备
set Condition 1 throughout the ship.
这不是演习 所有蝮蛇机驾驶员登机
This is not a drill. All Viper pilots report to your Vipers immediately.
赛昂舰队袭来
Inbound Cylon fleet.
重复  各就各位  各就各位
I repeat. Action stations, action stations,
全体舰队一级戒备
set Condition 1 throughout the ship.
这不是演习
This is not a drill.
天啊
Gods.
我们该怎么办?
What are we going to do?
卡拉狄加受袭  我们各司其职
The ship is under attack. We do our jobs.
到各自的岗位报到
Report to your stations.
到岗位报到?
Report to stations?
我叫少・泰 我是殖民舰队的一名军官
My name is Saul Tigh. I am an officer in the Colonial Fleet.
不论我还是什么
Whatever else I am,
不论这名字还有什么别的意义 我只想成为这个人
whatever else it means, that's the man I want to be.
如果我今天死了 我也要以这个身份死去
And if I die today, that's the man I'll be.
你到底去哪了?  一会再告诉你
Where the hell have you been? I'll tell you later.
把那架战机送进管道 把那梯子撤了! 把那梯子撤了!
Get that bird in the tube! Get those steps off! Get those steps off!
动起来 大家各就各位 我们被攻击了
Come on! All right, everybody. We're under attack!
快快
Let's go! Let's go!
装备好所有核武器
Arm and load all nuclear weapons.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
见到你真好  上校
It's good to see you, Colonel.
很高兴来到这里  上将
Good to be here, Admiral.
你可以信赖我
You can count on me.
这我从没怀疑过
I've never doubted it.
有事就请吩咐  总统阁下
I'm here if you need me, Madam President.
一定有出去的办法
MAN: "There must be some way out of here"
小丑对小偷如是说
Said the joker to the thief
这里的一切混乱不堪
"There's too much confusion"
待战机已出发
Alert Vipers are away.
想不清楚
"I can't get no relief"
谁在驾驶3号蝮蛇机?
Who's in Viper 3?
商人畅饮我的酒
"Businessmen, they drink my wine
农夫刨挖我的地
"Plowmen dig my earth
但他们没人
"None of them along the line
懂得那些东西的意义
"Know what any of it is worth"
卡拉狄加 我是阿波罗
Galactica, Apollo.
我在驾驶蝮蛇3号机 十点钟方向有不明飞船
I'm in Viper 3. I have a bogey at my 10.
我去查看一下
I'm gonna go check it out.
没必要如此激动
"No reason to get excited"
小偷悠闲地说道
The thief he kindly spoke
他去了哪里?
Where'd he go?
你他妈的去了哪里?
Where the frak did you go?
你我早是过来人
But you and I, we've been through that
我们的命运不只于此
And this is not our fate
怎么他妈回事?
Whoa! What the frak!
时间已经不早了
The hour is getting late
李
Hi, Lee.
卡拉?
Kara?
别怕  真的是我啦
Don't freak out. It really is me.
没事的
It's gonna be okay.
我到过地球了
I've been to Earth.
我知道它在哪里 我会带大家去那里
I know where it is, and I'm gonna take us there.
站在了望塔上
MAN: All along the watchtower
All along the watchtower